m 0 0 m 180 1 l 0 1 l 0 0 l 180 0
翻
译
低调付付
悉尼李映均
ScarSoul
翻
译
哨厨
西卡卡卡
Kenun
校对
&
后期
八秒
你以为列
总监
-=大红=-
片头推广合作洽谈
请联系普罗米修斯邮箱
PLMXS2016@GmaiL.com
我们不会写书
我们也不会拍电影
所以我们被理所当然的忽视了
很显然  美国历史上从未有过黑人牛仔的记录
-特里西亚·马蒂诺·瓦格纳
旧时西部的黑人牛仔：真实  轰动却又鲜为人知的历史
基于真实故事改编
这里曾经是土着民居住地
后来他们被驱逐
这里成为法外之地
阿肯色州  史密斯堡西部
这里没有美国法庭
也没有法律职权部门
1850年至1880年期间
这片土地上牺牲的治安官比之后130年间加起来都多
1875年
印第安人保留区
刚才一刹那
For a second there,
我以为我终于要上天堂了
I thought I finally done enough to see glory,
但是我的直觉告诉我
but my senses is telling me...
你不是天使
you ain't no angels.
看起来你多了些皱纹  少了些头发
Well, you add a few wrinkles, take away a little hair,
看来我们要抓到查理·斯托姆了
well, that'll look like we got Charlie Storm.
偷窃奶牛的盗贼
Cow rustling spirits pusher.
治安官  我现在这样很不舒服
Lawman, uh, I'm not exactly well here right now.
帮帮我把它弄出这个泥潭
Give me a little assistance getting out of this mire,
我  我会自首
and I'll... I'll turn myself in.
友好而又平和的
Nice and peaceful like.
要不还是你下马走出来吧
Well, why don't you just get down and walk out?
我会找人把你的马弄出来的
I'll arrange someone to get your mare.
该死  要是我能自己下马走出去
Damn. If I could walk out of here on my own strength,
你现在就只能跟我的马说话
you'd be having this conversation
而不是我
with only my horse here, not me.
巴斯  你怎么看
What do you surmise, Bass?
我们俩必须有个人把他弄出来
One of us'll have to bring him out of that pit.
你听到他刚才说的了
Well, you heard the man.
要是他出来了
If he could walk in that,
他就会跑去跟什么野人跳舞去了
he would be somewhat dancing with the savages.
另外
Besides,
我穿着制服可不是用来干这个的
I ain't dressed for the occasion.
别担心
Easy.
刚刚我想说的是
What I was trying to say is...
我走过去
I'd walk through,
把他扛在肩上回来交给你
carry him across my shoulders back to you for the iron.
所以你要在马都走不动的泥潭里
So you're gonna walk seven paces out there
一步步走到那边去
in mud that a horse can't walk in?
是的  长官
Yes, sir.
你要这么说  我倒是想看看
If you say it, I wanna see it.
治安官  你这是让这个黑鬼
Marshal, you're gonna get that nigger
来陪我一起送死
kill himself with me in the process.
老家伙  说话注意点
You need to watch your mouth, old man.
虽然里弗斯先生是个黑人
Mr. Reeves here he may be a negro,
但他是我的义警
but he's my posseman,
而且他可能会救你一命
and he may be the one that just saves your neck.
-我不会让他背我的  -你别无选择
- I ain't goin'. - Oh, you're goin'.
我不会上的
Oh, I ain't goin'.
如果他能成功走到你旁边
If he makes it out there to you,
你必须老实趴在他的肩膀上
you're very well going to get on his shoulders
好让他把你带回来
and make your way back over here.
不  我不
No, I won't!
我在这挺好的
I'm good right here,
还能喘气儿
above ground and breathing.
那个小黑鬼  他会陷进来的
That little nigger, he's gonna sink,
他会和我一样陷进来
and he's gonna sink with me in it.
老实讲我一点也不在乎
Quite frankly I don't really care
你是死是活
if you survive or not.
上面写了无论死活
Right here it says dead or alive.
里弗斯先生  你最好试着不要沉下去
Mr. Reeves, why don't you try not to sink
要不这种情况  你胳膊上免不了要挨一枪
before you get within an arm shot of this bank here?
我觉得泥巴粘在我的衣服上肯定不好洗
I don't think that mud's gonna remove from my linens very well.
治安官  你最好把我的讣告改正
Marshal, you better fix my obit right.
罪犯查理·斯托姆
The outlaw Charlie Storm,
印第安领地内的头号通缉犯
the most wanted outlaw in the Indian Territory,
孤身一人
took a fight on him
同8名美国治安官和16名义警搏斗
with eight US Marshals and sixteen possemen.
你觉得你能把我弄出去吗
You think you can get me out of this thing?
还真能
Well, I'll be.
查理·斯托姆  查理·斯托姆
Charlie Storm. Charlie Storm.
嗯
Yeah?
根据联邦法官艾萨克·帕克
By the power vested in me...
赋予我的权力
from the Federal Judge Isaac Parker,
我依法将你逮捕
boy, I place you under an arrest.
我们走  巴斯
Let's go, Bass.
怎么了
What is it now?
我想帮那匹马
Think I'm gonna help that mare.
帮它干什么
Help it do what?
帮它走出来
Help it out.
你知道的  我们没时间等你
You know we can't wait on you.
我们走  查理
Let's go, Charlie.
巴斯·里弗斯传
第一卷
地  狱  神  警
阿肯色州  史密斯堡
第一绞刑场
这些不法分子不守法纪
The outlaws here are unruly.
针对这些无法无天的人
The only solution to that unruliness
史密斯堡第一联邦法院
唯一的办法就是法治
is the rule of a law.
你被分配到这里是为了践行法律
The law that you were brought here to dispense.
艾萨克·C·帕克法官
Judge Isaac C. Parker...
在你判决过的所有犯人中
is there a man out of the ones that you sentenced
有没有从未伤害过一个无辜男女的
that didn't make a victim out of an innocent man or woman?
现在你可以把最后一个任务交给我了
Now, you can bring me the final part of the quest.
杀害朋友的那个人
The man that killed his friend.
我不是应该有个律师的吗
Shouldn't I have a counselor with me?
我并不想和你谈你的法定权利
I do not care to speak with you about your legal status.
我今天询问的目的是尽量和你谈一谈
The purpose of my inquiry today is to endeavor to speak with you
软化你的心
about softening your heart
好让你为去见上帝做好准备
in preparation for your inevitable meeting with God.
你从背后射杀了你最好的朋友
You shot your best friend in the back.
而且你离开这个世界进入永恒的时间
And it will not be long before you leave this world
也差不多快到了
and enter into eternity.
现在我不能怜悯你
Now, I cannot have mercy on you.
但是有一个人可以原谅你犯下的罪行
But there is one who can pardon your offenses,
有一位救世主  他的血足以
there is a savior whose blood is sufficient enough
洗去你灵魂上的污点
to wash this stain from your soul.
现在我求你去追寻他圣洁十字架的救赎
And I beg of you to seek the salvation of his Holy Cross,
因为我不能也不会赦免你的罪行
because I cannot and I shall not pardon your crimes.
愿上帝怜悯你
May God have mercy on you.
我没想到堡内这么多
I didn't realize the Fort was beaming
违法乱纪的行为
with so much unruly activity.
今天是帕克法官
Well, you know today is the day
送六个灵魂去见他们的造物主的日子
that Judge Parker gonna send six souls to meet their maker.
一次六个吗
Six? At one time?
帕克法官享受高效
Judge Parker relishes on efficiency.
什么人会为了高效
What kind of a man hangs six men
一次性吊死六个人
in the name of efficiency?
听起来更像是法外狂徒而不是执法者
Sound more like an outlaw than the law.
他就是法律
The law he is.
他21岁就通过了律师考试
He passed the bar exam when he was 21.
23岁就当上了市检察官
He was the city attorney at 23.
他因反对奴隶制离开了民主党
He left the democrats 'cause he arbors slavery.
好吧
Yeah.
你说了那么多
All that speak you speak,
我只记得他吊死了六个人
all my mind can remember is he's hung six souls.
-早  法官  -早
- Mornin', Judge. - Mornin'.
这是查理·斯托姆
This is Charlie Storm here,
他准备好接受审讯了
uh, he's ready for his arraignment.
治安官  你的犯人浑身都是泥
Marshal, your prisoner is covered in mud,
你身上却干干净净的
yet you remain pristine.
你知道一个好的治安官
Well, you know a good Marshal
懂得怎样去抓到自己的犯人
knows how to bring his man in
而不去弄脏自己
without sacrificing his stature.
-您明白吧  -明白
- You understand? - Very well.
把他带到监狱去
Bring him to the jailers,
对他的审讯安排在明天中午11:00左右
I'll arraign him tomorrow forenoon around 11:00.
你们都他妈离我远点
Y'all leave me the fuck alone.
你认识那个黑人巴斯·里弗斯吗
You know the colored man, Bass Reeves?
不认识
No.
不  不算认识
No, I can't say I do.
战争期间  他逃离了他的主人
He broke away from his master during the war.
烧掉他们的土地  抛弃他们的口音
Burned their land, their native tongue
在他来到这里之前
before coming here and...
里弗斯先生已经当了好几年义警了
Well, Mr. Reeves has been a posseman for a few years now.
我认为是时候给他升职了
I reckon it's time for a promotion.
你想让我提拔一个黑人做副治安官
You want me to promote a negro to Deputy Marshal?
是的
Yes, I do.
你为什么总是逼我做一些
Why do incessantly you push me
肯定会被解雇的事情
to do things that are sure to get me fired?
我没有做这种事
I'm doin' no such a thing.
我是你的助手  我是在辅助你
I'm your assistant, and I'm assisting you.
你倾听就好了
You'd do well just to listen.
你和我心里都清楚
You know as well as I do,
这个国家  表面上看着在进步
this country, as progressive as it pretends to be,
但是它还没准备好迎接一个黑人治安管
is not ready for a colored Marshal.
这些人们  他们只能适应这么多变化
These people, they can only handle so much change.
巴斯和我的阿尔奇在同一片土地上劳作
Bass and my Archie, homestead land together.
他会告诉你
He'd have told ya.
你找不到比他更会使枪的人了
You won't find a man more capable with a pistol.
我会告诉你
I'll tell you,
你找不到比他更忠于法律的人了
you won't find a man more loyal to the law.
你需要这样的副官
That's the kinda deputy you need.
晚上好  巴斯
Evenin', Bass.
晚上好  杰西
Evenin', Jessi.
你认识帕克法官吗
You know Judge Parker?
认识  女士
Yes, ma'am.
晚上好  先生
Evenin', sir.
晚上好
Evenin'.
待会见
I'll be seein' ya.
你是我们义警中的一员  是吗
You're one of our possemen, are you not?
是的  先生
Yes, sir.
你和那匹马
How did you and that horse
是怎么弄得全身是泥
find the occasion to be so stained by mud?
先生  这你得问问弗兰克斯治安官
You'd have to "ax" Marshal Franks, sir.
作为一名联邦法官  我正在问你  先生
As a federal judge, I'm inquiring of you now, sir,
老实说  我期望有个直截了当的回答
and frankly I expect nothing less than a straight answer here.
恕我直言
With all respect due ya,
弗兰克斯治安官是我的长官
Marshal Franks is the man I ride for.
我会付给你20美元
I will give you $20,
联邦工资
federal salary,
只要你对我坦白  先生
if you speak plainly to me, sir.
法官  无论多少钱
Judge, there is not a dollar amount
我都不会背叛我的雇主的
that would cause me to betray my employer.
得了吧  是我雇的他
Oh, come on, I employ him.
他又雇了你  所以严格的说是我雇了你
He employs you, so technically I employ you.
他付给你多少钱
What does he pay you anyway,
一周3美元吗
about three dollars a week?
给我讲讲一匹马
I'm offering you $20
我就给你20美元
to tell me about a horse.
我并不是这么认为的
I guess I just don't see it that way.
先生
Sir.
杰西小姐
Miss Jessi.
你想听点有意思的吗
You care to hear something humorous?
我今天见了弗兰克斯
I was with Franks today,
他身上干干净净的
and he was spit shine clean
但是他的犯人却跟你和那匹马一样
but his prisoner was covered about like you and that horse.
我跟他提这个事实的时候
When I mentioned that fact to him,
他甚至都没提到你的名字
he failed to even acknowledge you or your name.
主啊
Good Lord...
以耶稣基督的名
in Jesus' name,
让我知道自己在做正确的事情
let me know that I'm doing the right thing out here.
? 请赐予 ?
? Dona ?
? 我们平安 ?
? Nobis pacem ?
? 平安 ?
? Pacem ?
等等
Wait.
我坚信上帝只给人一次
I firmly believe that it's been appointed to man
生与死的机会
to live and die but once.
然而我知道站在我面前的这个灵魂
Yet before me stands a soul that I know
已经离开了这里
has departed from this place.
你杀了我的哥哥
You killed my brother.
不  等一下  我没有做这种事
No, wait, I did no such thing.
你哥哥  他罪有应得
Now, your brother, he did what he did.
他得到了正义的审判
Look, he got justice.
别这样
Don't do this.
杀了他
Kill him.
快点动手
Let's go.
他必须知道他为什么死  否则他的死没意义
He must know why he dies, or he dies in vain.
你说过了  现在该动手了
You spoke it. Now, we do it.
放下你的武器
Drop your arms.
为你的粗鲁
Came back to apologize...
道歉
for being rude.
你是科瑞克
You Creek?
不是
No.
你只是
You are...
一个孩子
but a boy.
我不是孩子
I'm not a boy.
我是鲁弗斯·巴克
I'm Rufus Buck.
走还是死
Leave or die.
鲁弗斯·巴克
Rufus Buck...
你该走了
You... should leave.
你不撤退吗
You don't retreat?
主啊
Lord above.
杰西说得对
Jessi was right about you.
她一点也没夸张
She didn't exaggerate at all.
我从来没见过一个人使用武器
I've never seen a man utilize his armaments
如此地快速精准
with such speed and efficiency.
你肯定能干掉那个男孩
I mean, you had that boy dead to rights
然后你就放他走了
and you just let him go.
谢谢
Thank you.
怎么了  先生
What's wrong, sir?
先生  我不是法官
Sir, I'm not a lawman.
而且他们有些人是白人
And some of those folks was white.
你还是目击者
And you a witness.
他们先挑衅的
Well, they drew first.
对你也对我
On you and me.
没错我是目击者
You're damn right I'm a witness.
那样也好
So be it.
如果你是目击者  那谁是法官
If you the witness, who gonna be the judge?
会有解决方法的
Well, there may be a solution.
巴斯
Bass.
怎么了
What's wrong?
我觉得  我可能会成为副治安官
I think I'm... I might be a Deputy Marshal.
你会怎样
You're what?
巴斯
Bass...
你胸前带上颗星星  你会成为靶子的
You put a star on your chest, you the target.
我一直都是靶子  没什么区别
I've always been a target, it's no different.
你是想让我变成寡妇吗
You're trying to make a widow of me?
我现在就离开然后你就省事了
I can just leave right now and save you the trouble.
我没有
I'm not...
放开我  巴斯·乔治·里弗斯
Let me go of me, Bass George Reeves.
让我一个人待会
Let me alone.
我们现在在农场里这样生活不是挺好的
We're doing just fine with you on the farm
时不时还跟治安官一起散步
and walking with the Marshal on occasion.
为什么是现在  巴斯  为什么
Why now, Bass? Why?
为什么
Why?
因为我们有六个人睡在隔壁房间
'Cause we got six souls sleeping in the next room.
好吧 你们三个绕到后面
All right, you three go around back.
我们从侧面包抄前线
We'll flank the front.
等等
Wait.
听着  吉姆  我知道我们已经走到这了
Look, Jim, I know we done come all this way,
但我觉得还是叫别人来帮帮我们
but I think it's wise for us to call someone to assist us.
你什么时候这么胆小的
Since when did you go yellowbelly?
我不胆小  兄弟
I ain't no yellowbelly, my friend.
但你也听过同样的故事吧
But you've heard the same stories
我有听说关于杜泽尔的
that I've heard about Dozier.
我们六个人  但还不足以能把他带出来
Six of us here, that ain't enough to bring him in.
你看到这个了吗
You see this?
你看到那些字了吗
You see those words?
上面写着美国司法部副治安官
That says United States Deputy Marshal.
我就是美国
I am the United States,
我们  代表美国
and we, as the United States,
要进去把杜泽尔带走
are gonna go in there and we're gonna take Dozier
回到帕克法官那里 为他的罪行负责
back to Judge Parker to answer for his crimes.
你们当中有人和汤姆一样胆小吗
And if any of you are yellow like Tom,
那么你就可以找个地方把自己埋了
then you can just go somewhere and bury your face
因为你们的国家不需要你们
'cause your country doesn't need you.
你想怎么说就怎么说吧  我要回家了
You say it like you want, but I'm going home.
你这样法官会要你的脑袋的
Judge is gonna have your head for this.
可能吧
Maybe.
你的脑袋也不保  因为你不听取道理
But he might have yours for not listening to reason.
你们两个绕到后面去
You two go around back.
就我们五个人
Just the five of us?
他就一个人  内德
It's one man, Ned.
我知道
I know.
鲍勃·杜泽尔
Bob Dozier!
我是司法部副治安官吉米·布鲁斯
I'm United States Deputy Marshal Jim Bruce.
我有你的逮捕令
I have a warrant for your arrest
阿肯色州史密斯堡地区法院签署的
out of the District Court in Fort Smith, Arkansas.
我们已经包围了你的房子
Your house is surrounded.
赶快自首吧
Turn yourself in now
避免不必要的流血
and prevent the unnecessary spilling of your blood.
鲍勃·杜泽尔
Bob Dozier.
这里是美国副治安官
The United States Deputy...
我听到了
I heard you cackle.
你重复几遍也不能够赋予你
Repeating yourself is not gonna endue you
管辖我的领土或我本人权力
with anymore jurisdiction over me
第一次也是一样
or my person than it did the first time.
你可能没听见
You might not have heard,
美国对印第安人保留区享有管辖权
but the United States has jurisdiction over the Indian Territory,
并且这里就是印第安人保留区
and this is the Indian Territory.
-是吗  -是的
- Is that right? - Yeah.
你的政府是如何获得
How did your government
非本国领土的管辖权的
get jurisdiction over a land it don't own?
你再说一遍
Pardon?
这块土地属于印第安
This land belongs to the Indian...
原始人的
savages.
在我看来  印第安人应该给你管辖权
It seems to me, the Indian should be giving you jurisdiction
因为是你们偷走了他们的每一寸土地
seeing as you stole every piece of land from them
然后把他们逼到这个地方
and you forced them on this territory,
他们没有对你们作出如此之事吧
I don't see them doing so.
先生  你肯定是搞错了
Sir, you must be mistaken,
政府是不需要许可的
the government doesn't ask for permission.
我们代表美国政府
We are the United States,
建议你出来
and we're advising you to come on out
不然我们会进去把你带出来的
or we're coming in there after you.
你们敢
I dare you.
好  进去抓他
Well, go get him.
还有人吗
Is anyone left?
有
Oh, yes.
副治安官吉米·布鲁斯
United States Deputy Marshal Jim Bruce,
还有人
someone is left.
我告诉过你  你管不了我和我的人
I told you, you do not have jurisdiction over me or my person
但你仍选择把我从梦中唤醒
yet you still choose to awaken me from my slumber,
导致我镇上的骚动
caused a ruckus in my town.
告诉我
Tell me something,
副治安官吉米·布鲁斯
Deputy Marshal Jim Bruce.
当一只老鼠侵入你家时你会怎么做
What do you do when a rodent invades your home?
这个问题是让你回答的  不是问着玩的
That question was not designed to be rhetorical.
-你杀了它  -没错
- You kill it? - Yes!
你不只是杀了它
You don't just kill it,
你杀了它再把它送回它的老窝
you kill it and you send it back to where it came from.
这样让所有的老鼠都知道发生了什么
This way all the other rodents see what happens
以防它们也想来我家
if they get the same idea.
收集他们携带的硬币
Gather the coins that he and the others carried.
和昨晚车上搜集到的放在一起
Put 'em with the gains from last night's coach.
并把它们给需要的家庭
And give it to the families that need it.
剩下的留给我们
Keep the rest so we may eat.
我向妇女儿童道歉
I apologize to the women and children
他们看到了这样的自卫场面
who had to witness that defense of self.
带他到保险库
Bring him to the vault...
把我的刀给我
and bring me my knife.
你个政府的狗腿子
You government man
给我捎个信
are gonna deliver a message for me.
必须完全准确
It needs to be unmistakable.
看着我
Look at me.
你能做到吗
Can you do that?
史密斯参议员
Senator Smith.
有消息说你可能在这边暗访
Word reached that you might be slumbering in these parts.
我听说这有几个人
And I heard there are several souls
在一个黑人的手上被杀了
that slumber in these parts at the hand of a black man.
其中一位是白人
One of those gentlemen was white.
现在  你知道即使在这里
Now, you know that even here,
像我们这样的进步
as progressive as we may be,
没有警徽的黑鬼
a negro cannot shoot a white man
绝不能射杀白人
without the protection of the shield.
那个是我们所说的袭击法官的白人吗
Is that what we call a white man that ambushes a judge?
一个绅士
A gentlemen?
-你误会我了  -无所谓
- You miss my... - No never mind,
因为我想任命那个人为副治安官
because I intend to name that man Deputy Marshal.
他迎难而上地保卫了自己的勇敢
Retroactively protecting his bravery last night.
你应该清楚
You do realize
如果你任命了那个黑鬼
that if you name that negro,
一个不明事理的黑人
the one that lacks the good sense
不明白不能射击白人  而且还真的开了枪
not to shoot down a white man, and he fails,
这将会是整个黑人的挫折
it would be a setback for the whole negro race.
-参议员  -不  不  不
- Senator... - No, no, no.
-参议员  我来告诉你  -你听我说完
- Senator, let me tell you... - You hear me out.
你听我说完
You hear me out.
我任命你是因为我相信你的判断
I nominated you because I trust your judgment.
格兰特总统相信黑人的自由
President Grant believes in the liberty of the negro.
他在南方的动乱中战斗着
He's fighting that unrest in the south.
但是为了保护我们的进步
But in order to protect our progress,
我们必须要培养黑人
we have to nurture the negro.
不只是让他们彻底自由
Not just set 'em fully free.
我是说  他们准备好成为自由人了
I mean, they are ready to be free,
但是他们准备好领导别人了吗
but are they ready to lead?
如果他失败了
And if he fails,
大概100年后都不会再有一个了
there's likely not to be another one around for 100 years.
所有你能告诉我关于这个黑人的什么
So can you tell me just what it is about this negro
让你能够相信他能够背负那样的重担吗
that makes you believe that he's worthy to carry that burden?
我不知道这是否公平
Well, I don't know if it's fair
把整个种族的重担都扛在他的肩上
to hoist the burden of an entire race upon his shoulders.
阁下  我知道你是教会的一员
Your Honor, I know you to be a man of the church...
是的  先生
Yes, sir.
还有法院
...and the law.
但是你愿意为那个人
But are you willing to gamble
赌上你的位置吗
your seat on the bench for that man?
我从不赌
I never gamble.
里弗斯副治安官
Deputy Marshal Reeves.
干得好  先生
Well done, sir.
法官  对不起  这些话我一直都想说
Judge, I'm sorry, but I've buried my words far too long.
我欣赏里弗斯先生是一个义警队员
I fancy Mr. Reeves here as a posseman.
你知道我欣赏
You know I do.
但是你给我们带来了耻辱
But you bring a dishonor.
命名他为副治安官是对我们的羞辱
A dishonor on the name of the Marshal by naming him.
弗兰克斯  不论他是不是黑人
Franks, negro or not,
在一天之内
in the course of a day,
我知道这个人去救了一匹马
I've known this man to rescue a horse,
营救一个罪犯并将他绳之以法
rescue an outlaw and bring him to justice,
从五个人手里救回法官
save a judge from perish from five men
拒绝了相当于他月薪几倍的报酬
and refuse a payment worth many times his monthly salary
只是为了提供信息
simply to provide information.
现在如果这些行为不足以让那个人
Now if those actions do not qualify that man there
成为我所在地区的副治安官
to ride as a Deputy Marshal in my district,
那我可能要把在座所有人的徽章都摘下来
then I might just pull the stars off every man here.
-法官  你犯了一个错  -包括你的
- Judge, you're making a mis... - Including yours.
没有罪犯会给黑人鞠躬的  哪怕他有徽章
No outlaw will bow for a black man with a badge.
他一周之内就会死  救救他吧
He'll be dead in a week, save them kids.
谁说的
Who said that?
现在  在这个法庭是有命令的
Now, there will be order in this court.
我会清理整个走廊
I'll clear this whole gallery.
送给帕克法官
Delivery here for Judge Parker.
我就是  放这儿吧
I'm Judge Parker, just set it there.
好的  先生
Oh, yes, sir.
法官大人  你或许不知道
Judge, you may not know,
但是这位里弗斯先生  他不识字
but Mr. Reeves here, he can't read.
如果他不识字  他就没法担任工作
And if he can't read, well, he can't ride.
是这样吗  巴斯
Is that right, Bass?
是的  先生
That's right, sir.
你能告诉我
Can you tell me...
你能像着了魔一样开枪
how is it that you come to shoot like a man possessed
但是却不识字
but you can't read?
我们这一代人生来就不自由
My generation was not born free.
我的老师教我开枪
My master taught me to shoot,
但是他拒绝教我识字
but he refused to teach me to read.
说是会让我变得更危险
Said that'd make me too dangerous.
比你带着枪还危险吗
More dangerous than you are with those Colts?
在哪
Where?
他如何以上帝的名义
How in God's good name
宣告逮捕令
is he going to read a warrant
以及确保抓对了人
and ensure that he brings in the right man?
我们不能提起诉讼
We don't need litigation by negligence...
因为这个黑人的疏忽
...caused by a negro.
告诉他们  弗兰克斯治安官
Tell 'em, Marshal Franks!
我丈夫可能不识字
My husband may not read...
但你们会尊重他的
but you will respect him.
我丈夫巴斯
My husband Bass...
可以是  也将是
can be and will be
值得信任的副手
a deputy worth rememberin'.
好的  我们听见了
Okay, now, we've heard you.
法庭上要保持秩序
We'll have order in this court.
我可以说几句吗
May I?
巴斯  你知道不行的
Now, Bass, you know I can't do that.
法庭上不允许有色人种发言
There are no coloreds allowed in the bar.
什么味道那么难闻
What is that awful smell in my courtroom?
没事
Okay.
法官
Judge?
我感觉味道是从这个箱子里发出来的
I suspect the smell is coming from, uh, this here package.
打开它
Well, open it up.
法官  你不会想看的
Judge, you ain't gonna like it.
法官  真的太可怕了
Horrible, Judge, horrible.
天啊
Jesus!
那个人头是个预示
That head was a promise.
也是一个会被实现的预示
It was a promise and it was a promise fulfilled.
让他爱在哪儿在哪儿吧
Now, you let him stay where he is.
如果他进城来了
Should he make his way into town
那你就让法律来对付他
then you let the law have its way with him.
布鲁斯做了件傻事
Bruce went on a fool's errand
他被送到家时只剩一个脑袋
and he returned home slight of his body.
尽管如此
Well, be that as it may.
这里有人愿意
Is there anyone here...
来执行这个逮捕令吗
who will execute service of this here warrant?
有人吗
Anyone?
没人
No one
在本法庭的权威下
under the authority of this court here
可以在法律之外行事
shall stand above the law.
法官  能接下这任务的人
Judge, ain't nobody ill enough in their right mind
一定病得没治了
to take on that assignment.
你在猛兽的栖息地追捕它
You chase an animal in his own habitat
无异于去送死
is simply suicide.
我愿意
I will.
真好
Oh, that's good.
里弗斯先生
Mr. Reeves...
你不是副手
you aren't a deputy.
先生  看来我们都有各自的问题和解决办法
It seems, sir, that we both have a problem and a solution.
你需要有人来结束杜泽尔的罪行
You need someone to put an end to Dozier's terror.
我也需要证明
And I need to prove
我会是一个非常有能力的副手
that I would be a more than capable deputy.
一箭双雕  一石二鸟
Both problems solved by the same solution.
如果我能把他抓回来  你要给我佩戴徽章
If I can bring him back you'll put a badge on my chest.
这么说这个人
So this man here,
你们许多人觉得他不配
who many of you feel isn't worthy enough
穿上你们的靴子成为副治安官
to strap your boots.
但他比你们所有人加起来都有勇气
This man has more courage than any of you all combined.
现在  如果我同意他的请求
Now, if I grant this request...
有人愿意和他一起去吗
is there anybody that will ride with him?
我自己去
I ride alone.
不  里弗斯先生
No, Mr. Reeves,
尽管你很想这么做
as much as it might be your inclination to do so,
还是不会让你只身前往的
you will not ride alone.
我的命令
My orders.
谁想和他一起去
Who will ride with him?
没人愿意回到地狱去抓那个人
Ain't nobody going back to hell to chase that man.
我们都想保住自身性命
We're kinda partial to having our heads attached to our torso.
我愿意
I will.
赦免我的罪
Pardon my crimes,
我会和他一起去
shit, I'd ride with the nigger.
你一个亡命之徒
Well, you wouldn't be the first outlaw.
想通过成为一名义警重回正道
You put on a straight path by being a posseman.
先生  你被指控犯有一些严重罪行
You are charged with some serious crimes, sir.
如果被关进监狱可能会下场很惨
You would likely fall upon the ground at foot in prison,
况且你已如此年迈
being as old as you are.
在和里弗斯先生执行完这次任务后
Upon execution of this warrant with Mr. Reeves here...
我会赦免你的
I will pardon you.
-他叫什么名字  -斯托姆
- What's his name? - Storm.
查理·斯托姆
Charlie Storm.
很高兴认识你
Pleased to meet you.
好吧  你没那么坏
All right, you ain't so bad.
之前有人把他们全吊死了
Somebody hung all them sumbitches.
我明白了
Oh, I get it.
我们有一个黑人和一个老头
We got a negro and a senile old man
要把这里最臭名昭着的罪犯抓回来
to bring in the most notorious outlaw in this territory.
上帝保佑这个国家
God save this country.
? 你能听到吗 ?
? Can you hear me? ?
? 快逃 ?
? Run away ?
? 自由  你能听到吗 ?
? Freedom, can you hear me? ?
? 我虽然行过 ?
? Yea, though I walk in the valley ?
? 死荫的幽谷 ?
? Of the shadow of death ?
? 也不怕遭害 ?
? I will fear no evil ?
? 主啊  你是否可以听见 ?
? Father, Father, can't you hear me? ?
? 是否可以听见我们的呼唤 ?
? Father, Father, hear us callin'... ?
爸爸  你可以带上我的星星
You can wear my star, daddy.
? 奔向家中的你 ?
?...runnin' home to you ?
? 因为你与我同在 ?
? For thou art with me ?
? 你的杖  你的竿 ?
? Thy rod and thy staff ?
? 都安慰我 ?
? They comfort me ?
你现在去睡觉吧
You go to bed now.
-好吗  -好吧
- Yeah? - Okay.
? 耶和华又要给受欺压的人?
? The Lord will also be a refuge ?
? 以庇护 ?
? For the oppressed ?
? 在他们患难之时 ?
? A refuge in the times ?
? 以庇护 ?
? Of trouble ?
? 主啊  你能否听见 ?
? Father, Father, can't you hear me? ?
? 我仁慈的主 ?
? Father, Father... ?
你所做的
What'd you do...
当全世界都不相信你的时候
when the whole world doesn't believe in you?
你让他们每一个都成为信徒
You make believers out of every last one of 'em.
要下雨了
That rain's coming down.
我们要不要找个地方避雨
Should we get some cover?
我想下不了多久
I think it'll pass.
你觉得离开镇上很明智吗
You think it's smart to leave town?
我想不会再有人来烦我们了
I don't think anyone will bother us again.
关键是政府不想输
One thing about the government is they don't like to lose.
如果形势不利  就不要挑起争端
Won't pick a fight if the decks are stacked.
而这里  我们拥有主动权
Around here, we own the decks.
他们明白
They know that.
我们继续赶路吧
Let's ride.
小姐  我现在需要见帕克法官
I need to see Judge Parker now, missy.
我接到他的上级格兰特总统的命令
I have orders from his boss, President Grant,
不要任命巴斯·里弗斯为美国治安官
not to appoint Bass Reeves US Marshal
并立即逮捕他
and to have him arrested forthwith.
对不起  参议员
I'm sorry, Senator.
帕克法官今天不上班
Judge Parker is not in the office today.
里弗斯先生也不在
Nor is Mr. Reeves.
那他们到底在哪
Well, where in the hell is he?
我不知道  先生
I don't know, sir.
但他们都有自己的家
But they both have a home.
我一定会把消息传达给他们
I'll be sure to pass the message along.
祝你们今天愉快
Have a good day now.
内莉
Nellie,
你能让巴斯出来吗
would you send Bass out?
好让他给上级做个汇报
So we can allow him to answer to the proper authorities.
他没有什么好汇报的
There ain't nothin' he needs to answer for.
先生们  里弗斯先生不在
Gentlemen, Mr. Reeves is not here.
你们应该把枪放下
And it would behoove you to lay those arms aside.
如果她无辜的孩子受到伤害
Should one of her innocent children get harmed,
我可不知道
I'd dare not be the man
该如何向巴斯·里弗斯交代
to stand between that person and Bass Reeves.
把枪收起来  伙计们
Put your arms away, boys.
请你也收起来吧  女士
It'd be nice if you did too, ma'am.
我接到史密斯参议员送来的
I have orders here from President Grant,
来自格兰特总统的命令
delivered from Senator Smith
里弗斯先生需要接受庭审
that Mr. Reeves stand trial.
他们带回罪犯后
Should they succeed in their endeavor,
我会亲自跟格兰特总统谈的
I'll take it up with President Grant myself.
如果没有
If not...
没有如果
No "if not."
巴斯·里弗斯快回来了
Bass Reeves is coming home.
当然  对不起  女士
'Course. Sorry, ma'am.
你看到那些人
You see all them men
都被法官送进了坟墓吗
Judge sent to their grave?
该死的混蛋比我这亡命徒好不到哪去
Sumbitch is no better than the outlaws out here.
如果我们得不到一些有用的回复
You know, I wanna just pull my horse up,
我会转身就回去
turn around if I don't get some straight talk.
来告诉我
All right, riddle me this,
一个黑鬼怎么得到土地
how does a nigger get land?
你无权拥有土地  对吧
You can't own land, can you?
你有个漂亮的老婆
You got a pretty wife, you know.
你这种丑八怪怎么会有这么漂亮的老婆
How did a ugly sumbitch like you get such a pretty wife?
不许说我老婆
Don't you speak of my wife.
原来你不是哑巴
Oh, so he can talk.
我需要说话时才说
I talk when I need to.
-别说我老婆  -好吧
- And don't you speak of my wife. - All right.
别担心
Don't you worry about it.
我才不想说呢
I'm not gonna speak at all.
我不知道你是否意识到了
I don't know if you realize this.
没有我你是抓不到他的
You can't get him without me.
我不需要你也不需要任何人
I don't need you or nobody out here.
我们已经赶了两天路了
We've been riding for two days
连个鬼影都没见到
but haven't seen a soul.
你有计划吗
Do you even have a plan
还是睁开眼就只顾走
or you just get up and go?
没时间做计划了
No time to plan.
胡说  总有时间做计划的
Well, shit, there's always time for plannin'.
笨蛋和精英的差距
Plannin' is the difference between being
就在于会不会做计划
a cow rustler and spirit pusher
因为杀人而被通缉
and being wanted for killing somebody
还不得不面对判你绞刑的法官
having to face that hanging judge of yours.
你想说什么
What you trying to say?
你真的杀了人然后逃走了吗
You done kill somebody and got away with it?
我只是说说而已
I'm just saying what I said.
闭嘴  查理
Yo, shut up, Charlie.
你只会虚张声势
You ain't nothin' but bluster.
但我们可能一锤子都打不响
But we can't even hit a lick.
白给的都抓不住
Can't even hit a buffalo in a herd.
就算让我自己骑马去底特律
You know, I'm startin' to think riding to Detroit
也会比和你在一起
would have been easier on my nerves
轻松得多
than riding with you.
给你的宽恕并不取决于
You know, your pardon doesn't depend on
你说了多少话
how many words you speak.
我懂
Oh, I know.
我只是找点乐子
I just find joy in talking.
而且  你应该感谢你歌颂的上帝
Besides, you should thank that God you sing to,
我的射术也很不错
I can shoot pretty good too.
好吧
Yeah, okay.
Okay?
你就说个"好吧"
好的
Yeah, okay.
-随便指个地方  -我们没有时间去
- Point. - We do not have time for...
不 不  你是在质疑我的能力
No, no, no, no, you just called my ability into question.
让我证明给你看  好让你放心
Let me put your mind at ease.
让我证明你是对是错吧
I'm either gonna prove you right or wrong.
来吧
Now, point.
那块石头
That rock.
哪一块
Which one?
好吧  让我靠近一点
All right, let me bring it closer.
不  你不能靠那么近
No, no, no, you don't have to bring it closer.
-中间那块大石头  -我看到了
- The big rock in between... - I got you.
-在树中间的那块  -好了  我看见了
...in between the tree. I got you. I got you.
不是我开的枪
That wasn't me.
快走
Let's go.
你为什么那样做
Why did you tear off like that?
他们需要帮助  我就帮了
They needed help, I helped.
你还是不懂  是吧
You don't get it, do you?
他们几个刚刚可能就死了
Them people might've been dead.
你没有计划就上了
You just go off without no plan.
就那么冲上去了
Just tear off like that.
他们没教你们老黑什么是耐心吗
Don't they teach you niggers anything about patience?
真是头浣熊
You're such a coon.
也有黑鬼的意思  这里指他没耐心
这是你最后一次在我旁边说这个词
That is the last time you use that word around me.
你就因为这个打我
That's why you swung on me?
我不是那个意思
I... I don't mean nothing by it.
我老爹教我这么说的
That's what my pappy taught me.
种马
Horse.
黑  好了好了
Nig... Okay, okay, okay.
我说出口的不是那个意思
It don't mean nothin' coming from me.
我听着像那个意思
It means something coming to me.
好吧
Well, all right.
操
Shit.
我只是想说
All I'm tryin' to say is...
你像浣熊不像乌鸦
you're all coon and no crow.
-什么  -浣熊  浣熊
- What? - Coon. Coon.
你知道这个动物吧
You know, the animal, coon?
它闯进你家  想拿什么就拿什么
He'll come into your house, he takes what he wants
然后就走了  它胆子很大
and he leaves, he's fearless.
再说乌鸦  它想要吃坚果
Now, a crow, a crow wants a nut,
又不想把它鸟嘴给折了
he don't wanna break his beak.
它就会把坚果放在路中间
He'd drop that nut in the middle of the road,
等一辆马车路过把它碾碎
wait for a wagon to come by, break it,
然后再去捡起它的食物然后离开
pick it up, take his bounty and leave.
这叫做耐心
It's called patience.
你在讲什么鬼话  查理·斯托姆
Now you makin' no sense, Charlie Storm.
我讲的可不是鬼话
I'm makin' a lot of sense.
你会懂的
And you'll get it...
你懂的时候就懂了
as soon as you get it.
两位先生
Gentlemen.
抱歉打扰你们兄弟俩吵架  但是
Sorry to disturb your brotherly spat, but...
太阳马上就落山了  你们还没吵完吗
the sun'll be setting before you settle.
? 时间到了 ?
? The time has come ?
? 我们是时候分别了 ?
? For us to part in the partin' band ?
? 那么再会了  朋友 ?
? So, farewell, friends ?
? 再会 ?
? Farewell ?
真好听
Sweet song.
你们为什么被追杀
Why you getting shot at?
我们把黑人从南边
Well, we been moving our people from the south
带到堪萨斯的这片沃土
to this fertile ground in Kansas.
从72年就开始了
Been doin' that since '72.
但是联邦政府
But the federal government
开始从南边撤军
been moving their troops out the south,
所以我们要找一条新路线
so we had to find a new route.
你可以过来
You should come.
我们刚刚建立起我们的第一块聚居地
We just planted our first colony.
我们在吸引人来
We've been fetching for people.
现在大概有600人
Got about 600 right now.
我有地  这是你的地吗
I got land. You own it?
是我的宅基地
I homesteaded it.
66年修改法律时分到的
'66 when the law changed.
成了公民
Became a citizen.
联邦政府批准了我
Federal government approved me.
宅基地
Homestead.
你听说过税吗
You heard of taxes?
地主呢
Landlords?
在纳什维尔那我是殡葬员
I was a undertaker back there in Nashville.
有时候我要埋葬当父亲的
And sometimes I'd have to bury fathers.
可能第二天早晨
Maybe by the next mornin'.
那地主会去母亲那里
That landlord would go to their mother.
她大概 有六七个小孩
She'd have about six or seven children.
那地主就会告诉她
And that landlord would tell her,
"你丈夫死前欠我钱"
"Your husband owed me before he died."
然后他会说
And then he'd say,
"你要搬走
"You have to go some other place.
我照顾不了你"
I cannot take care of you."
那是我会注意到的事
Now, that's something I would take notice of.
迟早你会发现
Sooner or later you'll find her
她从破烂不堪的房子里出来
comin' out of some disorderly house,
那些小孩
and those children...
进了州监狱
state prison.
这故事感觉过分了
Sounds like tales of excess.
还以为老林肯让你们自由了
Thought old Abe set you free.
尽管法律说我们是自由的
Although the law say we free,
南边还是会悬赏我们的人头
the South still sends for us with money on our heads.
他们叫南方赏金团
They call that a southern bounty group.
国家南边已经乱套了  先生
The southern country is out of joint, sir.
往西边发展了
And it's coming west.
他们已经没有地了
They running out of land already...
而且他们来的时候
and when they come...
把所有的病也都带来了
they bringing all their ills with 'em.
我知道
I know.
我的血管里流着白人的血
The blood of a white man run through my veins.
国家南边还是有些白人是好人
There is some good white men in the southern country,
但不是大多数  而你可能就是大多数
but it ain't the majority, to which you just might fit.
是啊
Yeah.
可能我是
Maybe I would.
可能你只是不知道你想要什么
Maybe you just don't know what you want.
但我知道
But I do.
我想闭上眼睛睡觉
I want to shut my eyes
没有人在我耳朵旁边
without the sound of white oppression
抱怨白人种族压迫
coursing through my ears.
我还有任务
I got a mission.
我需要好好休息
And I'm gonna need to be rested for it.
要完成我们几天前开始的工作
Gotta finish some work we started days ago.
我们可以把你们带到下一个镇上
We can take you to the next town over.
你们有匹马还有马车
See that you get a wagon and a horse.
你们在切罗基人的领土会没事的
You'll be all right in Cherokee land.
北美土着易洛魁印第安人
朋友们
Fellas.
我觉得你们和这位小姐可能迷路了
I think you and the lady... might be lost.
在我的领土你不必这样
You don't have to do that in my territory.
你的领土
Your territory?
像你这么强壮帅气的男人
Man as handsome and strong as yourself
不需要来担心我们
needn't worry about us.
我们只是瞎转转
We just wandering.
我们也不想惹麻烦
We don't want any trouble either.
我的几个弟兄被枪杀了
Couple of my men were gunned down.
我们在找该负责的人
We're lookin' for who's responsible.
-那不会是  -你为什么在乎这个
- That wouldn't be... - Why do you care?
我为什么在乎
Why do I care?
我是说  他们是你的亲戚吗
I'm sayin', are they kin to you?
他们是我亲戚我才会去在乎吗
They gotta be kin for me to care?
可能不是
Maybe not.
但你去接近陌生人收集情报
But to approach a stranger seeking information,
我觉得要么是亲戚要么就是疯了
I would judge you to be kin or crazy.
我不是亲戚
Well, I ain't kin.
那你肯定是疯了
Well, then you must be crazy.
我还不知道你们的名字
I didn't get your name.
我是弗兰克·詹姆斯
Well, I'm Frank James.
这是我弟弟杰西
This is my brother, Jesse.
这位爆竹  她是贝儿
And this firecracker right here, well, that's Belle.
-贝儿  -贝儿·斯塔尔
- Belle. - Belle Starr...
来自山姆斯塔尔帮
of the Sam Starr gang.
如果你认识这个名字
So if that name means somethin',
我建议你好走不送
I suggest you be on your way.
詹姆斯
James.
永格帮的吗
Of the Younger gang?
对  他们是这么叫的
Yeah, they call us that.
谢谢你们朋友的信息
Well, thanks for the information on your compadre.
我想我们要
I think we'll be...
去找到他然后恭喜他
going to find him now and congratulate him.
好吧
Okay.
那洞里面你们放了什么
What'd you put inside the hole?
只是我们的狗
Just our dog.
对狗来说这洞很大
It's a mighty big hole for a dog.
他是条很大的狗
He was a mighty big dog.
你是他亲戚
You kin to him?
我长得像他吗
Do I look like him?
有点
A bit.
但是你口音不像
But you don't sound like him, though.
你是哪的人
Where you from?
苏格兰
Scotland.
-那是哪  -欧洲
- Where's that? - Europe.
我读到过  平克顿是那的人
I read about it. Pinkerton's from there.
平克顿
Pinkerton?
那个抓不到杰西·詹姆斯的傻逼吗
You mean that motherfucker can't catch Jesse James?
对
Yeah.
他也就和他"爹地"一样能干
He's about as skillful as his "daady" too.
"爹地"
"Daady."
怎么了  巴斯
What's goin' on, Bass?
我们快走
We gotta go.
现在有个计划
Well, havin' a plan would come in
就有用多了  是吧
real handy about now, wouldn't it?
你是谁
Who are you?
巴斯
Bass...
里弗斯
Reeves.
我们不想惹麻烦
We don't want no trouble.
可能麻烦找上你了
Maybe trouble seeks you.
先生  原谅我这位朋友
Sir, excuse my friend here, he...
他说他知道这里的路
He said he knew this land here.
如果我们知道这是你们地
If we knew this was your piece,
我们原本可以避免这次不幸的对峙
we could have avoided this whole unfortunate confrontation.
闭嘴  老头
Shut up, old man.
好的先生
Yes, sir.
你说你的名字是巴斯·里弗斯
You say your name was Bass Reeves?
是谁在问
Who ask?
我的天
My goodness,
还以为你是迪克·格拉斯的手下
thought you was Dick Glass' boys
跟着我们来寻仇的呢
riding behind us to get their piece of vengeance.
山姆
Sam?
山姆·六杀手
Sam Sixkiller.
这位是山姆·六杀手
This here is Sam Sixkiller.
我离开我的人之后他收留了我
He took me in when I left my man...
我离开了战场
I left the war.
救了我的命
Saved my life.
山姆·六杀手是什么名字
What kinda name is Sam Sixkiller?
这位是查理·斯托姆
And this here is Charlie Storm.
你的朋友吗
Your friends?
你在这边干什么  巴斯
What are you doing in these parts, Bass?
还以为你精致到不想再来这里了
I thought you was too fancy to visit these lands again, huh?
我现在在往马斯科吉赶
I'm just headin' to Muskogee for now.
我也是
Me too.
太阳快落山了
Sun's settin'.
来镇上休息吧
Why don't you come rest up in town?
也照顾一下他们
Get that looked after.
巴斯
Bass.
我们公开邀请你们加入我们
You all have an open invitation to join us.
我们想但是不能
Well, we would but we can't.
巴斯家里还有人呢
Bass got a family back home
还指着我们回去完成任务
depending on us getting back finishing this mission.
我明白
I understand.
小心点  那会让你昏昏沉沉的
You be careful, that'll make you drowsy.
你相信他说的吗
You believe Pep?
关于什么
About what?
白人拿走了他的地
The white man took his land?
你也是白人  你想要地吗
Well, you white, you want land?
我有过地
Oh, I had land.
他们也拿走了
They took it too.
他们是谁
They, they who?
先是邦联的拿走了
Well, Confederates took it first.
美国南部邦联
然后联邦士兵找上门来了
That brought the Union soldiers to my doorstep.
然后地被联邦拿走了
Then the Union took it.
美国联邦政府
没有还
Kept it.
你妻子呢
What about your wife,
后代呢
offspring?
都没有
No.
这次任务是什么
So what's this mission?
追捕任务吗
You on the hunt?
是啊
Yeah.
追捕谁呢
And who'd that be?
鲍勃·杜泽尔
Bob Dozier.
我们喝一杯吧
We should get a drink.
-我不喝  -我来替我俩喝一杯
I don't... I'll drink for the both of us.
? 苏珊娜  别为我哭泣 ?
? Oh, Susanna, oh, don't you cry for me ?
? 我从阿拉巴马来  膝上放了把五弦琴 ?
? I come from Alabama with a banjo on my knee ?
? 苏珊娜  别为我哭泣 ?
? Oh, Susanna, oh, don't you cry for me ?
? 我从阿拉巴马来  膝上放了把五弦琴 ?
? I come from Alabama with a banjo on my knee ?
? 我跳上电线杆  沿河顺流而下 ?
? I jumped aboard the telegraph and traveled down the river ?
? 电流突然涌动 ?
? Electric fluid magnified ?
? 杀死了五百只虱子 ?
? And killed five hundred chigger ?
? 苏珊娜  别为我哭泣 ?
? Oh, Susanna, oh, don't you cry for me ?
? 我从阿拉巴马来  膝上放了把五弦琴 ?
? I come from Alabama with a banjo on my knee ?
巴斯
Bass.
你听得清说话吗
You hear a single utterance?
抱歉  哥们
I apologize, man.
本想和那边的查理说几句话的
Thought I was gonna have to have a word with Charlie over there.
他还挺有个性的  不是吗
He's quite a character, isn't he?
你想找的那个人
Well, that man you seek,
他要多坏有多坏
he is as bad as they come.
我们同为血肉之躯
We cut from the same clay,
共享同一片天空
breathe the same air.
如果他真像你说的那么坏
If he's as bad as you say he is,
那我又能怎样
what does that make me?
迪克·格拉斯都不及那个人的小脚趾卑鄙
Dick Glass isn't as mean as that man's pinkie toe.
我从不临阵脱逃  你也是知道的
I don't run from a fight, and you know that,
但我不会和他纠缠
but I would not pursue him.
我从没有遇到过像他这么卑鄙
I ain't never met a man that mean
还开枪这么快的人
or that fast...
连你都比不上他  巴斯
not even you, Bass.
我们可是士别三日了
Well, you haven't seen me for a while.
没错  我的确挺久不见你了
No. No, I haven't.
听着  他给法官寄了一个人头
Look, he sent a man's head
眼睛上钉着一个警徽
with a badge attached to the eye to a judge.
别问我  我也不知道他在哪里
Well, you never mind 'cause I don't know where he is.
没什么人知道
Not many do.
悠着点  大伙儿
Whoa, whoa. Easy, guys.
悠着点
Easy.
只有我
It's just me.
我有条带给杜泽尔的口信
I have a message for Dozier.
任何放任弱者去死的
Any creature that would leave to die
生物
the delicate...
理应受到任何惩罚
they warrant any punishment that befalls them.
黑鬼
Negro.
还有一个话痨印第安人
Speaks Creek.
在他们出发前打死五个人
Shot five men before they could draw.
他在找我是吗
Right. He's looking for me?
大概是我上次语气不够强烈把
Well, I guess my last message wasn't loud enough.
政府的人想找我  不管是不是黑鬼
Government man wants to find me, negro or not...
我会让他轻松点的
I'll make it easy for him.
? 苏珊娜 ?
? Oh, Susanna ?
? 别为我哭泣 ?
? Oh, don't you cry for me ?
? 我从阿拉巴马来  膝上放了把五弦琴 ?
? I come from Alabama with a banjo on my knee ?
你怎么没在唱歌  巴斯
How come you ain't singing, Bass?
? 苏珊娜 ?
? Oh, Susanna ?
? 别为我哭泣 ?
? Oh, don't you cry for me ?
? 我跳上电线杆 ?
? Oh, I jumped aboard the telegraph ?
? 沿河顺流而下 ?
? And traveled down the river ?
? 电流涌动 ?
? Electric fluid magnified ?
? 杀死了五百只虱子 ?
? And killed five hundred chigger ?
巴斯  你听我唱了吗
Hey, Bass, did you hear me?
我没唱"黑鬼"
No "nigger."
我唱的是"虱子"
Chigger.
? 杀死了五百只虱子 ?
? Killed five hundred chigger ?
巴斯
Hey, Bass.
那些马  我们把马留在
The horses. We left the horses back...
-它们会没事的  -好的
- They're gonna be just fine. - Okay.
我们早上就去取马
We'll get them in the morning.
好的
Okay.
喂
Hey.
你真不错
You're all right.
你是个好人  巴斯
You're all right, Bass.
巴斯
Bass.
来了
Yeah.
什么事  山姆
What is it, Sam?
从没想过你会成为治安官
Just never thought of you as a lawman.
你还被法律害得那么惨
Not after what the law did to you.
法律让我身陷囹圄
The law put me in chains...
但法律也让我重见天日
but the law also set me free.
现在我必须保持自由  为了养我的孩子们
Now I got six little ones that I need to stay free.
六个吗
Six?
天呐  巴斯
Gracious Bass,
你可真把那可怜的女人累坏了  不是吗
you wearing that poor woman out, ain't you?
我听说有个黑小子在找我
I hear there's a black boy seeking my whereabouts.
是他来了
That's him.
-是杜泽尔  -别动
That's Dozier. Don't.
不用找了  我来了
Seek no more, here I am.
巴斯
Bass.
他闯进的是我的镇子
He's riding into my town.
我们一起拿下他  巴斯
We take him together, Bass.
不行  他是为了找我才闯进你的镇子的
No. For he rides into your town for me.
他要的是我
It's me he gets.
你无法独自面对他
Well, you can't face them alone.
就算我不行
Even if I can't,
你只有一只手
you with your one arm...
也帮不了什么忙
it's not gonna be much help.
我一只手射击比大多数人两只手射得都准
I can shoot with one better than most with two,
你也是知道的  巴斯
you know that, Bass.
六杀手
Sixkiller...
你曾救过一个溺水的男孩
you saved a drowning boy once.
现在轮到他报答你了
Now, let that man repay you.
你有两分钟
You got two minutes.
不用两分钟
I won't need 'em.
你不会临阵脱逃了吧
Don't tell me you went coward on me.
该死
Well, I'll be damned.
那个小印第安人说的没错
That young Indian was right.
一个黑鬼在找我
A negro on a quest for me.
鲍勃·杜泽尔
Bob Dozier.
我有你的逮捕令
I have a warrant... for your arrest.
黑鬼拿的逮捕令在我这里可没什么权力
Well, a negro and that warrant has no authority here.
但这逮捕令有权力
Oh, but it does.
我也有
And so do I.
我会原谅你的无知
I'm gonna excuse your ignorance,
给你一个保命的机会
give you a chance to claim your life.
谢谢  杜泽尔先生
Thank you, Mr. Dozier.
我会回去
I will return.
但要先执行这个逮捕令
Not without executing this warrant.
不论死活
Dead... or alive.
你想这么来是吗
That the way you want it to be?
只能这么来
That's the way it is.
你先来  小子
Your move, boy.
不论生死
Dead or alive.
来拿呀  小子
Come for it, boy.
"巴斯已经一周没有露面了
"Bass hasn't been seen in a week.
恐怕他已经死了
And he's feared dead.
格兰特总统两天后会来
President Grant will be here in two days."
我们一起拿下他  巴斯
We take him together, Bass.
六杀手  你曾救过一个溺水的孩子
Sixkiller, you saved a drowning boy once.
? 一切 ?
? And everything ?
? 都会没事 ?
? Will be all right ?
? 祈祷 ?
? Pray on ?
你要去哪儿
Where you off to?
还以为你睡着了呢
Thought you were still asleep.
现在醒了
Well, I'm up now.
去西班牙堡
Spanish Fort.
骑马大概半天到
About a half a day's ride.
你想自己去吗
You thinkin' about going alone?
他只有一只手臂  你又喝了酒
He got one arm, you liquored.
会拖慢我的
It'd slow me down.
好吧
All right.
那就走吧
Go on, then.
让你妻子变成寡妇  小孩变成孤儿
Make a widow of your wife and orphan of them kids.
走啊
Go on!
牛逼的巴斯·里弗斯
Badass Bass Reeves.
独自骑行之人
Man who rides with nobody by his side.
他妈的
Shit.
走啊
Well, go on!
他也许笨嘴拙舌  但言辞尖锐
He may be slow of tongue, but his words are sharp.
也许杜泽尔是有些人手
Now, Dozier may have some men...
但他用不上了
but he don't need them anymore.
你有什么用
Well, what good are you?
你只有一只手臂
You got one arm.
你不喝酒连一天都坚持不下去
You can't even go a day without drinking.
这里就是边境了
The border's right there.
你们怎么不逃跑啊
Why ain't you run?
你不用跟我走完
You don't have to finish.
我看到你对杜泽尔的手下做了什么
I... I seen what you did to Dozier's men.
你要是能有点帮手
If you only had some help.
我的意思是
I mean...
我想说的是
What I'm trying to say is,
你要是知道了这些还想继续
if you insist on goin' after what you now know...
那就去他的吧
then fuck it!
我也一起
I'll go, too.
我们最好希望我还能跑得动
But we better pray my boots become unstuck.
我也能跑
Yeah, I could run.
我直接就能冲过边界
I could just head for the border.
想拿什么拿什么
Keep taking what I want.
谁不想给我我就杀了他
Shoot anybody who doesn't want to give it to me.
我也能做点事
Or maybe I could do somethin'.
做点
You know, somethin'...
有意义的事
worthy.
搞个像样的讣告
My proper obit. Hmm?
做点值得记录的事
Somethin' worth writing about.
你怎么不回家  你才是有家室的那个
Why don't you go home? You're the one with the family.
你应该把这蠢差事
You should leave this fool's errand
留给这个懦夫
to this coward here
还有这个老醉鬼
and this old drunk outlaw.
我要是走了
If I leave...
还有谁能把你们从愚蠢中拯救出来
who's gonna save you from the fool's folly?
好样的
Attaboy.
走你
Go!
你用油膏了我的头
"Thou anointest my head with oil,
出自《圣经  诗篇23》
使我的杯满溢
"my cup runneth over.
我一生一世必有福份和慈爱
"Surely goodness and mercy shall follow me
紧随着我
all the days of my life."
四十个人少了三个
Forty men off three.
我可不赌这把  赢面太小
Not odds I'd take if I was gamblin'.
是啊  要是这你都能赢  你就成传说了
Yeah, you win at them odds, you a legend.
好
All right.
等天黑再行动
We wait till nightfall.
围剿这个小镇
Circle the town.
然后在天亮前突袭他们
And then we jump 'em before daybreak.
这
That's, uh...
这就是你想做的吗
That's what you wanna do?
这就是我们来的原因
That's why we came.
我们以前围剿过这里  但那时有六个人
We circled this before and it was six of us...
五个
Well, five.
而且他是一个人
And he was alone.
他还活下来了
And he still lives.
你们是突袭的他吗
You got him by surprise?
没有  那个蠢货宣战了
No, the stupid bastard announced.
你可不能敲魔鬼的门
Well, you don't knock on the devil's door
问能否进去
and ask to come in.
我们等到天黑再行动
We wait till nightfall.
我们要悄悄过去
We go in real quiet like.
把站岗的人都干掉
You can take out every man that's posted.
就可以去到房子那里
You can make your way through the house.
然后去他的卧室  包围那个混蛋
You get to his bedroom, you surround the motherfucker.
他就和你一起出来了
He comes out with you.
不论生死
Dead or alive.
那就等天黑
Nightfall it is.
? 有那么一段 ?
? There ?
? 时光 ?
? Was a time ?
? 一切 ?
? Everything ?
? 都很棒 ?
? So supreme ?
接着我把他丢了出去
Then I threw that man
正中窗户
right through the window.
然后老大骑马赶来
And the boss rides up.
点燃炸药  扔进屋子
Lights the dynamite, tosses in the house.
我们骑马离去  然后炸弹响了
We ride off and then, boom!
大地颤动
The whole ground shook.
故事结束
That's about it.
不喝了
No... I'm...
不要了
No, no.
我要去睡个好觉  缓解疲惫
I'm gonna go and sleep off this fun.
明天按计划进行
The stage comes through tomorrow.
如果成功了  够我们所有人吃一年
If we pull this off the right way, this town eats for a year.
? 也许你逃避了很久 ?
? You may run for a long time ?
? 逃避了 ?
? Run on ?
? 很久 ?
? For a long time ?
? 逃避了 ?
? Run on ?
? 很久 ?
? For a long time ?
? 我告诉你  上帝不会饶过你 ?
? Let me tell you that God's gonna cut you down ?
? 上帝对我说话那么动听 ?
? My God spoke and He spoke so sweet ?
? 我以为听到了天使的舞步声 ?
? I thought I heard the shuffle of angels' feet ?
? 他用手抵住着我的头 ?
? And He put a hand upon my head ?
? 全能的主啊  我来转述主的话 ?
? Great God Almighty, I'll tell you what He said ?
是时候了
It's time.
? 去告诉那长舌的骗子 ?
? Go tell the long tongue liar ?
? 去告诉那个午夜车手 ?
? Tell that midnight rider ?
? 告诉那赌徒  流浪汉  诽谤者 ?
? Tell the gamblers, the ramblers, the backbiters ?
? 告诉他们迟早会面临主的盛怒 ?
? Tell 'em that God's gonna cut them down ?
伙计  你看起来有点迷路
Look a little lost there, fella.
我只是路过
I was just passing through.
你是执法官吗
You the law?
在这附近
I don't know of any colored lawmen
我可不知道这种肤色的治安官
around these parts.
当然不是
No!
别动
Oh, easy.
如果你们是来找杜泽尔的  我们就别斗了
If you've come for Dozier, we ain't got no quarrel.
我在这做事
I do what I do out here.
只是不想死而言
Just not to die.
杜泽尔把他的马拴在哪
Where does Dozier keep his horse?
在他家外面
Outside his house.
尤其是当治安官来了后
Specially since that Marshal showed up.
树林那边就很危险
Woods are dangerous over there.
你是个幸运儿
You're a lucky man.
主  我现在该不该行动
Lord, tell me if I should act now.
主  我很抱歉
I'm sorry, Lord.
我有点希望你能大声点
I was kinda hoping you'd be louder...
但是你没说不可以
but you didn't say no.
你杀害了我的一个挚友
You killed a dear friend of mine.
你还想杀了我
You tried to kill me, too.
你还没死
You didn't die.
我以前说过
Like, I said before...
根据联邦法庭赋予我的权力
I'm here to return you to Fort Smith...
我来这把你带回史密斯堡
by the power given to me by the federal court.
你想笑就笑
You can cackle all you want.
你和联邦法庭都无权管我
You and no federal court has any jurisdiction over me.
也许现在就把你就地正法了
Then maybe I'll just shoot you dead now.
只需扣下扳机
Just pull this trigger.
你才不会
You won't.
因为你不是我
'Cause you ain't me.
你不想先开枪
You don't want to shoot first,
或者说被等我手下包围再开枪  不是吗
or you'd have done so when my men surrounded you, no?
可我会射杀你
But me, I'd shoot you dead.
你最好瞄准点
You better be a good shot.
我瞄的很准
I'm better than good.
你知道我曾经是一位副治安官吗
Did you know I used to be a Deputy Marshal?
那无所谓
It doesn't matter.
有的
It matters.
可你的政府
But your government...
指控我抢劫罪
accused me of robbery.
剥夺我的警徽
Stripped me of my star,
他们对我刑讯逼供
they lashed me to confess.
拉我入狱  我失去了家人
Locked me up. I lost my family.
面对黄热病
Yellow fever.
我措手无策
Couldn't do nothin'.
我的安妮是我见过最纯洁无暇的宝贝
My Annie was the purest thing I ever seen.
柯丽娜也是  但是他们在黄泉相会了
So was my Corina, but they met the dirt.
而我成为了亡命之徒
Like an outlaw.
因为法律是不合理的
'Cause the law wasn't reasonable.
而我的妻子和女儿死了
And my wife and my baby died.
这让我清楚意识到
It was made very clear to me
我要去追求我最初的欲望
that I was to pursue my earnest desires.
因为谋生就是活命
'Cause livin' is to live...
然后死去
and then you die.
可能正是如此
That may well be.
吉米·布鲁斯  山姆·六杀手和贝儿·斯塔尔的兄弟
Jim Bruce, Sam Sixkiller, Belle Starr's brother
都死了  而你却活着
no longer live, and you are.
你应该在底特律监狱偿命
But you gonna do your livin' and dyin' in Detroit prison.
你今晚别想离开这  黑人小子
Well, you ain't leavin' here tonight, colored boy.
你最好明白这点
You should have thought this through.
查理
Charlie.
抓住他
Get him!
查理
Charlie!
抓住那个混蛋
Go get that sumbitch.
现在这里太危险了
Now, it's too dangerous in here.
我会马上回来
I'm gonna be back.
如果我没能回来  你要确保带着
And if I don't, you make sure you take
内莉和我的孩子们去该去的地方
Nellie and my little ones where they need to be.
黑人和那通缉令在这都没法律效力
A negro and that warrant has no authority here.
你根本不知道杜泽尔的位置
You ain't got no idea where Dozier is.
加油  巴斯
Come on, Bass
巴斯
Bass.
你的职业是什么
What do you do?
加油
Cheer up.
我看好你
I gotta give it to you.
你马上就要拿下我了
Really come close to unseating me
比那些白人治安官都强
than any white lawman.
你和我可以组成一支无敌的队伍
You and me would have made a hell of a team
日日夜夜
any other night.
无论人种
Nigger and all.
你现在怎么不出来
Why don't you come out now
跟我公平对决
and we could have a fair fight?
治安官  我都跟你说了
I told you, lawman...
政府管不着我
government doesn't have any jurisdiction over me.
无论生死
Dead or alive.
谢谢你
Thank you.
老头  你是打足精神上马
Well, old man, you got the spirit to ride,
还是在这让你退休
or should I just retire you here?
你想得美
You wish.
汤姆  你来吗
Tom, you comin'?
不  我觉得
No, I think, uh...
西班牙堡那里需要一些人手
Spanish Fort is a place that needs some lookin' after.
好吧
Well...
如果有人说汤姆·皮克特是个懦夫
if anybody ever says Tom Pinkerton's a coward...
你就让他们来找我
you just send 'em my way.
多谢
Thanks.
走吧  杰克
Come on, Jake.
嘿  查理
Hey, Charlie!
我能跑得动了
I got my boots unstuck.
你疯了
You crazy.
主  你的信徒们犯了错
You gentlemen are makin' a mistake.
不  法官阁下
No, Your Honor.
是你犯下的错
You made the mistake.
史密斯堡的英雄
Good people of Fort Smith,
将青史留名
gather the paper writers.
查理·斯托姆和巴斯·里弗斯
Charlie Storm and Bass Reeves
从鬼门关回来了
has returned with the bounty.
你们不会相信这些
You ain't gonna believe this.
没有人说我们能够做到  不是吗
None of you said we could do it, did you?
我们成功抓捕了
We done brought back an outlaw
那个杀害多个治安官
that has killed many lawmen,
和无辜百姓的狂徒
innocent people and others.
我们抓到了鲍勃·杜泽尔
We done brought back Bob Dozier!
内莉  内莉
Nellie. Nellie!
巴斯回来了
Bass is back.
他们杀了杜泽尔
They killed Dozier.
我以为你死了
I thought you was dead.
没有
No.
我一直在考虑我的葬礼
I've been thinkin' about my obit.
又来了
Oh, not this again.
你已经不再是逃犯了
You are no longer an outlaw.
这就是关键
That's my point.
治安官的葬礼该怎样比较好
What's a good obit for a lawman?
巴斯·里弗斯
Bass Reeves.
因为某些原因
For some reason...
我觉得你还有大把时间
I think you're gonna have plenty of time.
你知道  小心些没坏处
Well, you know, you can't be too careful.
先生们
Gentlemen.
里弗斯先生
Mr. Reeves.
在任何地方的法庭
You may enter the bar...
无论是不是我主持
here and in any court I preside in,
只要我还有一口气  你就可以涉足法律界
as long as there's breath in my body.
请您上前来
Please, sir, come forward.
法官大人  你还有东西给我们的吧
You have somethin' for us, Judge?
我有一堆委任状要交给你们
I have a stack of warrants for you.
报酬不低于三千
No less than three thousand.
多谢
Ma'am.
里弗斯先生
Well, Mr. Reeves,
你觉得你需要这个
I think you'll need this.
二位先生还需要什么帮助吗
Will you gentlemen be needing any additional help?
没了
Nah. Nah.
? 快逃 ?
? Run away ?
? 自由  你可听到我的呼唤 ?
? Freedom, can you hear me? ?
? 快逃 ?
? Run away ?
? 自由  你可听到我的呼唤 ?
? Freedom, can you hear me? ?